Guide to the Benson J. Lossing Papers, 1861-1956
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Benson J. Lossing Papers
1861-1956
Lossing, Benson J. (Benson John), 1813-1891
1.3 cubic feet (4 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Correspondence concerning Vassar College activities, speeches, and engagements with Lyman Abbott, Nathan Bishop, Stephan M. Buckingham, Charles S. Farrar, Milo P. Jewett, Maria Mitchell, John H. Raymond, Lucy M. Salmon, James Monroe Taylor, Matthew Vassar, and Henry Van Ingen, with some family correspondence. Other items include his notes from a trip to Washington, D.C. in 1861, and miscellaneous programs.
Biographical Note
Benson John Lossing, LL.D. (1813-1891) was born and raised in Dutchess County, New York. A prominent engraver, illustrator, and historian, Lossing became one of the original trustees of Vassar College in 1861. He was an active member of the Board of Trustees until his death in 1891, taking stands on such issues as the incorporation of the word "Female" in Vassar Female College. His historical works include The Pictorial Field Book of the Revolution, The American Centenary, and Vassar College and Its Founder. Lossing made most of the engravings in his various works himself, although in later years he was assisted by his daughter, Helen Lossing. Lossing was married twice, first to Alice Barritt, niece of his former employer and partner; and then to Helen Sweet, who died in 1912.
Source: Paine, Nathaniel. A Biographical Notice of Benson John Lossing, LL.D. Worcester, MA: Worcester Society of Antiquity, 1892.
Scope and Content Note
The Lossing Papers consist mainly of correspondence, sketches by Lossing, and memorabilia. The correspondence is divided into three sections, including correspondence regarding Vassar College and correspondence to others and from others. The bulk of the collection was purchased by Vassar College in 1948 from H. Armour Smith of the Hudson River Museum of Yonkers. Additional items from Lossing's estate were donated by Richard Chamberlain in 1976.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
Vassar College Biographical Files
James Monroe Taylor Papers
Separated Materials
Letters from the Benson J. Lossing Papers were removed from the collection during the in the 1980s. Four letters from Benson Lossing to John Howard Raymond and one letter to his wife, Cornelia E. Raymond were moved to the John Howard Raymond Papers (Box 4). One letter to Cornelia Morse Raymond were moved to the Cornelia Morse Raymond Papers (Box 1). Two letters to James Monroe Taylor were moved to the James Monroe Taylor Papers (Box 7). Two letters to Cyrus Swan may have been moved as well but the collection is unprocessed and the letters are not easily identified.
Subject Headings
Names:
Abbott, Lyman, 1835-1922; Bishop, Nathan, 1808-1880; Buckingham, Stephen M.; Farrar, Charles S. (Charles Samuel), 1826-1903; Jewett, Milo P.; Mitchell, Maria, 1818-1889; Raymond, John H. (John Howard), 1814-1878; Salmon, Lucy Maynard, 1853-1927; Taylor, James Monroe, 1848-1916; Vassar, Matthew, 1792-1868; Van Ingen, Henry; Lossing family
Organizations:
Vassar College
Subjects:
Wood-engraving; Family--New York (State); Women--Education; Women's colleges--New York (State)--Poughkeepsie; Editors; Authors
Places:
Washington (D.C.)--Description
Encoding Information
Encoded by Elizabeth Clarke, May 2007. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, August 2025.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from H. Armour Smith in 1948. Other materials donated by Richard Chamberlain in 1976.
Runge note donated in 2001(M2014-014).
Greenleaf correspondence purchased in 2009 (M2009-007).
Sketches in Folder 7.11 were the gift of Jonathan L. Clark, in honor of Leslie Joan Friedman '69, 2025. (M2025-010)
Series List
- Series I. Correspondence, 1855-1891
- Series II. Correspondence Regarding Vassar College, 1868-1888
- Series III. Correspondence to Others from Others, 1867-1891
- Series IV. Vassar College Board of Trustees, 1864-1891
- Series V. Manuscripts and Notes by Benson Lossing, 1856-1956
- Series VI. Sketches by Benson Lossing, 1837-1886
- Series VII. Photographs, circa 1860s - 1979
- Series VIII. Memorabilia, 1723-1979
Container List
- Series I. CORRESPONDENCE, 1855-1891
  - Correspondence to Benson Lossing
    - Abbott, Lyman, 1881; (1 item) (Folder 1.1)
    - Alvord, C.A., 1867; (1 item) (Folder 1.2)
    - Backus, Truman J., 1872-1879; (4 items) (Folder 1.3)
    - Beadle, Edward L., 1871; (1 item) (Folder 1.4)
    - Belknap, T., 1872; (2 items) (Folder 1.5)
    - Bessard, Blanche, 1865; (1 item) (Folder 1.6)
    - Bishop, Nathan, 1867-1872; (6 items) (Folder 1.7)
    - Bissell, George E., 1877-1880, undated; (10 items) (Folder 1.8)
    - Boone, W.W., 1868, undated; (2 items) (Folder 1.9)
    - Braislin, Priscilla H., 1878; (1 item) (Folder 1.10)
    - Bright, Edward, 1874; (2 items) (Folder 1.11)
    - Brown, Helen D., 1881; (1 item) (Folder 1.12)
    - Buckingham, C.J., 1871-1887; (2 items) (Folder 1.13)
    - Buckingham, Stephen M., 1870-1878; (6 items) (Folder 1.14)
    - Buckingham, Stephen M., 1881-1887; (9 items) (Folder 1.15)
    - Buttré, J.C., 1867; (2 items) (Folder 1.16)
    - Caldwell, Samuel L., 1880-1883; (3 items) (Folder 1.17)
    - Clapp, George, 1864; (1 item) (Folder 1.18)
    - Constant, Samuel, 1881; (1 item) (Folder 1.19)
    - Cook, J. Harvey, 1890; (1 item) (Folder 1.20)
    - Cooley, LeRoy C., 1875-1880; (10 items) (Folder 1.21)
    - Cowles, Augustus, 1890; (6 items) (Folder 1.22)
    - Dame, Mary, 1874-1875; (2 items) (Folder 1.23)
    - Dwight, William B., 1879-1890; (12 items) (Folder 1.24)
    - Ellis, George E., 1870; (1 item) (Folder 1.25)
    - Ely, Achsah M., 1889; (2 items) (Folder 1.26)
    - Farrar, Charles S., 1867-1879; (7 items) (Folder 1.27)
    - Fletcher, J.C., 1868; (1 item) (Folder 1.28)
    - Fuller, Samuel L., 1877; (2 items) (Folder 1.29)
    - Giraud, Jacob P. Jr., 1867; (6 items) (Folder 1.30)
    - Glover, Lewis F., 1865; (1 item) (Folder 1.31)
    - Haddock, Lorenzo K., 1864; (1 item) (Folder 1.32)
    - Hall, B.H., 1864; (1 item) (Folder 1.33)
    - Hinkel, Charles J., 1873-1890; (4 items) (Folder 1.34)
    - Hofmann, Laura S., 1867; (1 item) (Folder 1.35)
    - Homberger, William, 1867; (1 item) (Folder 1.36)
    - Howard, George W. [Lossing's response written on opposite side], 1885; (1 item) (Folder 1.37)
    - Innis, George, 1885; (1 item) (Folder 1.38)
    - Jewett, Milo P., 1861-1882, undated; (14 items) (Folder 1.39)
    - Jones, Horatio Gates, 1867; (1 item) (Folder 1.40)
    - Knapp, William, undated; (1 item) (Folder 1.41)
    - Lathrop, Edward, 1883-1885; (4 items) (Folder 2.1)
    - Lyman, Hannah W., 1868; (3 items) (Folder 2.2)
    - Lynch, Anne C., undated; (1 item) (Folder 2.3)
    - McAllister, John A., 1869; (2 items) (Folder 2.4)
    - Macdonald, Wilson, 1876; (2 items) (Folder 2.5)
    - McLellan, C.H. P., 1857; (3 items) (Folder 2.6)
    - Mitchell, Maria, 1871-1888, undated; (4 items) (Folder 2.7)
    - Moreau, Charles C., 1867; (1 item) (Folder 2.8)
    - Moreau, John B., 1867; (1 item) (Folder 2.9)
    - Morris, Ida W., 1879; (1 item) (Folder 2.10)
    - Müller, F.F., 1864; (2 items) (Folder 2.11)
    - Orton, James, 1869; (4 items) (Folder 2.12)
    - Orton, James, 1870-1875; (8 items) (Folder 2.13)
    - Pierson, H.W., 1861; (4 items) (Folder 2.14)
    - Pomeroy, Laura S., 1877-1880, undated; (7 items) (Folder 2.15)
    - Porter and Coates, 1875; (1 item) (Folder 2.16)
    - Powell, Elizabeth M., 1867; (3 items) (Folder 2.17)
    - Putnam, G.H., 1871; (2 items) (Folder 2.18)
    - Raymond, John H., 1865-1868; (7 items) (Folder 2.19)
    - Raymond, John H., 1869; (7 items) (Folder 2.20)
    - Raymond, John H., 1871-1872; (11 items) (Folder 2.21)
    - Raymond, John H., 1873-1878; (5 items) (Folder 2.22)
    - Raymond, Mrs. John H., 1879; (1 item) (Folder 2.23)
    - Reichel, W.C., 1864; (2 items) (Folder 2.24)
    - Ripley, George, 1863; (2 items [photocopy—original at Morgan Library, New York, NY]) (Folder 2.25)
    - Ritter, Frederick L., 1869-1881; (9 items) (Folder 2.26)
    - Salmon, Lucy Maynard, 1888-1890; (9 items) (Folder 2.27)
    - Sanford, Katharine S., undated; (1 item) (Folder 2.28)
    - Sayre, John N., 1865; (1 item) (Folder 2.29)
    - Schou, James N., 1866-1869; (3 items) (Folder 2.30)
    - Schuyler, Louise Lee, 1878; (1 item) (Folder 2.31)
    - Sheldon, Smith, 1869; (1 item) (Folder 2.32)
    - Shroff, K.M., 1874; (1 item) (Folder 2.33)
    - Siddons, J. Henry, 1867; (1 item) (Folder 2.34)
    - Spencer, Cornelia, 1870 May 25; (2 items) (Folder 2.35)
    - Spencer, J.A., 1862-1863; (7 items) (Folder 2.36)
    - Spencer, J.A., 1864; (3 items) (Folder 2.37)
    - Strong, Augustus H., 1885; (1 item) (Folder 3.1)
    - Swan, Cyrus, 1861-1867; (6 items) (Folder 3.2)
    - Taylor, James Monroe, 1886-1890; (7 items) (Folder 3.3)
    - Taylor, James Monroe, 1891; (3 items) (Folder 3.4)
    - Taylor, Robert, 1891; (2 items) (Folder 3.5)
    - Tenney, Sanborn, 1867; (2 items) (Folder 3.6)
    - Van Ingen, Henry, 1867-1871; (13 items) (Folder 3.7)
    - Van Ingen, Henry, 1873-1879; (7 items) (Folder 3.8)
    - Van Ingen, Henry, undated; (6 items) (Folder 3.9)
    - Vanni, Antonio, 1870; (1 item) (Folder 3.10)
    - Vassar, John Guy Jr., 1867; (1 item) (Folder 3.11)
    - Vassar, Matthew, 1864-1868, undated; (8 items) (Folder 3.12)
    - Vassar, Matthew Jr., 1856-1878, undated; (8 items) (Folder 3.13)
    - Wait, Maria, 1868; (1 item) (Folder 3.14)
    - West, Charles E., 1891; (2 items) (Folder 3.15)
    - Wight, Rezin A., 1885 Nov 6; (2 items) (Folder 3.16)
    - Wright, J.H., 1861; (1 item) (Folder 3.17)
  - Correspondence from Benson Lossing
    - Benton, Judge, 1855; (3 items) (Folder 3.18)
    - Buckingham, Stephen M., 1878 Jun 21; (5 items) (Folder 3.19)
    - Caldwell, Samuel L., 1881 Sep 15, 19; (2 items) (Folder 3.20)
    - Greenleaf, Thomas, 1883 Jan-Mar; (3 items) (Folder 3.40)
    - Innis, George, 1865-1881; (4 items) (Folder 3.21)
    - Jewett, Milo P., 1882 Mar 1; (1 item) (Folder 3.22)
    - Lathrop, Edward, 1885 Jul 23; (2 items) (Folder 3.23)
    - Lossing, Mrs. Benson J., 1883; (1 item) (Folder 3.24)
    - Lyman, Hannah, 1867 Mar 4; (1 item) (Folder 3.25)
    - Mitchell, Maria, 1870 Jul 17; (1 item) (Folder 3.26)
    - Mitchell, Maria, 1880-1886; (3 items [TS from letters in the files of the Library of the Maria Mitchell Association, Nantucket]) (Folder 3.27)
    - Morse, Samuel F.B., 1862 Jul 28; (2 items) (Folder 3.28)
    - Phoenix, L. Whitney, 1867 Jul; (1 item, photocopy) (Folder 3.29)
    - [Runge?], John F., 1867 Jun; (1 item, ALS) (Folder 3.41)
    - Salmon, Lucy Maynard, 1888 Feb 2 - Mar 10; (2 items, TS) (Folder 3.30)
    - Saunders, Frederick, 1889 Dec 3; (1 item) (Folder 3.31)
    - Sheldon, Smith, 1882 Aug; (4 items) (Folder 3.32)
    - Strong, Augustus H., 1885 Aug 10; ( 2 items) (Folder 3.33)
    - Tyler, Moses Colt, 1872-1873; (16 items, TS and Photostats) (Folder 3.34)
    - Undated fragments in Lossing's hand, (2 items) (Folder 3.35)
    - Vassar, Matthew, 1864 Jun 6 - Sep 1; (2 items) (Folder 3.36)
    - Vassar, Matthew, 1867 Feb 2 - Mar 29; (3 items) (Folder 3.37)
    - Vassar, Matthew Jr., 1872-1879; (4 items) (Folder 3.38)
    - Wight, Rezin A., 1885 Oct 28; (1 item) (Folder 3.39)
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE REGARDING VASSAR COLLEGE, 1867-1891
  - V.C. Alumnae Association, circa 1876; (3 items) (Folder 4.1)
  - V.C. Alumnae, Boston, 1884; (11 items) (Folder 4.2)
  - V.C. Art, Department of, reports by Professor Henry Van Ingen, 1869-1871, undated; (8 items) (Folder 4.3)
  - V.C. Art School, 1877; (1 item) (Folder 4.4)
  - V.C. Cecilia Society, 1869; (2 items) (Folder 4.5)
  - V.C. Faculty Appointments/Candidates, 1883; (1 item) (Folder 4.6)
  - V.C. Library [letters from Truman Backus, Stephen Buckingham, G.P. Putnam, James Thorne Harper], 1868-1888; (6 items) (Folder 4.7)
  - V.C. Maria Mitchell Endowment Fund, 1889; (1 item) (Folder 4.8)
  - V.C. Music, Department of, undated; (1 item) (Folder 4.9)
  - V.C. Observatory [correspondence re: telescope defect], 1868; (6 items) (Folder 4.10)
  - V.C. President. Candidates, 1878-1885; (4 items) (Folder 4.11)
  - V.C. President, Office of, 1869; (4 items) (Folder 4.12)
  - V.C. Trustees. Candidates, 1872; (2 items) (Folder 4.13)
- SERIES III. CORRESPONDENCE TO OTHERS FROM OTHERS, 1864-1891
  - Avery, Alida C. to Henry Van Ingen, 1867; (1 item) (Folder 4.14)
  - Bissell, George E. to Col. Morgan L. Smith, 1879; (2 items) (Folder 4.15)
  - Lossing, Mrs. Helen to son, 1883; (1 item) (Folder 4.16)
  - Rely, Julia A. to Mrs. Helen Lossing, 1880; (1 item) (Folder 4.17)
  - Smith, Col. Morgan L. to Matthew Vassar, 1877; (2 items) (Folder 4.18)
  - Taylor, James Monroe to Mrs. Helen Lossing, 1891; (1 item) (Folder 4.19)
  - Van Ingen, Henry to Lucy Maynard Salmon, undated; (1 item) (Folder 4.20)
  - Van Ingen, Henry to Robert Titus, 1891; (2 items) (Folder 4.21)
- SERIES IV. VASSAR COLLEGE BOARD OF TRUSTEES, 1864-1891
  - Addresses by Benson Lossing to the Board of Trustees
    - Address to Board of Trustees re: college name change, [1866]; (MS, 8 p., 1 draft) (Folder 4.22)
    - Address to Executive Committee re: commissioning Laura Hofmann to construct a bronze statue of Matthew Vassar, 1868; (MS, 6 p., 2 drafts) (Folder 4.23)
    - Address to Board of Trustees re: Committee on Cabinet and Apparatus, [1869]; (MS, 5 p., 1 draft) (Folder 4.24)
    - Address to Committee on Faculty and Studies of VC re: introducing study of history into curriculum, 1872; (MS/TS, 11 p., 2 copies) (Folder 4.25)
    - Address to Executive Committee re: Matthew Vassar Jr.'s will, 1882; (MS, 20 p., 3 drafts) (Folder 4.26)
  - Communications of the Board of Trustees
    - Communications re: committees, 1873-1876; (2 p.) (Folder 4.27)
    - Communications to the Board of Trustees of Vassar College By Its Founder; Lossing's personal, annotated copy of the booklet, 1869; (65 p.) (Folder 4.28)
    - Notices of meetings, 1864-1891; (13 p.) (Folder 4.29)
    - Orders of business, [1872-1890]; (3 p.) (Folder 4.30)
    - VC President's Office, 1888; (2 p.) (Folder 4.31)
  - Resolutions by the Board of Trustees
    - Resolutions, 1867-1890; (11 p.) (Folder 4.32)
    - Resolutions, undated; (3 p.) (Folder 4.33)
- SERIES V. MANUSCRIPTS AND NOTES BY LOSSING, 1856-1956
  - Manuscripts by or about Lossing
    - Memo by Lossing of a conversation with Samuel F.B. Morse, 1857 Jan 17; (MS, 3 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.1)
    - Notes of a trip to Washington, Baltimore, and back to Poughkeepsie, 1861 Nov 11-27; (MS, 11 p., 1 draft [p.1-10, 12; p. 11 missing]) (Folder 5.2)
    - Vassar College and Its Founder list of Lossing cuts in the library, Published 1867, undated; (TS, 3 p.) (Folder 5.3)
    - Index to Vassar College and Its Founder, Published 1867, undated; (TS, 40 p., 2 copies) (Folder 5.4)
    - Biographical Sketch of Matthew Vassar, 1890; (TS, 22 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.5)
    - An Extended Annotation of Benson J. Lossing's "Pictorial Field-Book of the Revolution" by Lorinda Ocheltree (VC 1957) for History 265, 1956; (TS, 27 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.6)
    - Remarks concerning some of the portraits at Vassar College, undated; (MS, 13 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.7)
    - Secret History of the Founding of Vassar College…, undated; (MS, 22 p., 1 draft) (Folder 5.8)
  - Notes by Benson Lossing
    - References to and extracts from Walt Whitman's "Leaves of Grass,", 1856; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 5.9)
    - Notes re: Elliot's portrait of Matthew Vassar, 1862; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 5.10)
    - Clipping and notes re: opening of Vassar College, circa 1865; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 5.11)
    - Notes re: President's address to alumnae on conferring degrees, circa 1871; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 5.12)
    - Notes re: will of Matthew Vassar Jr., 1882; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 5.13)
    - Notes re: Giraud Collection of North American Birds, undated; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 5.14)
    - Notes re: List of Engravings wanted by the English Dept., undated; (MS, 1 p.) (Folder 5.15)
    - Notes re: Milo P. Jewett, undated; (MS, 2 p.) (Folder 5.16)
    - Miscellaneous notes re: VC, undated; (MS, 3 p.) (Folder 5.17)
- SERIES VI. SKETCHES BY BENSON LOSSING, 1837-1886
  - Sketches of Buildings
    - Van Kleeck House: Photostats of sketch and accompanying newspaper article, 1837; (4 items) (Folder 5.18)
    - Van Kleeck House: small drawing with description on back, signed by Lossing; large drawing, 1864; (2 items) (Folder 5.19)
    - Van Kleeck House: description of Van Kleeck House, written and signed by Lossing, 1864; (1 item, oversized) (Folder 8.1)
    - Lossing's birthplace Beekman Ville, Dutchess County, signed by Lossing, 1846; (1 item) (Folder 5.20)
    - Tower of First Reformed Dutch Church, newspaper clipping and description signed by Lossing on back, 1857; (1 item) (Folder 5.21)
    - Our house among the Katzberg's—Ira Scribner's, 1861; (1 item) (Folder 5.22)
    - Haight House in Chestnut Ridge, undated; (1 item) (Folder 5.23)
    - Lossing's library, NW corner, undated; (1 item, oversized) (Folder 8.2)
    - Lossing's library, SE corner, undated; (1 item, oversized) (Folder 8.3)
    - Samuel Dorland's [Helen Lossing Johnson's great-grandfather] house near Arthursburg, undated; (1 item) (Folder 5.24)
    - The Vanderburg House, Poughquag, NY, undated; (1 item) (Folder 5.25)
    - "Danforth's House" (presumably Jonathan Danforth's homestead in Billerica, MA), undated; (4.5 x 6.5 inches, graphite and watercolor) (Folder 7.11)
  - Sketches of Nature Scenes
    - Interior of Dover Stone Church; flowers of may apple and hog apple, 1857; (1 item) (Folder 5.26)
    - [The Raquette], 1859; (1 item, photostat) (Folder 5.27)
    - Storm in the Donder Berg Coffer Dam, 1860; (1 item) (Folder 5.28)
    - Upper Planterkill Fall, 1861; (1 item) (Folder 5.29)
    - Rombout Patent, 1885; (1 item) (Folder 5.30)
    - Canal basin at Albany, undated; (1 item) (Folder 5.31)
    - Great Boom, 4 miles above Glen's Falls, undated; (1 item, photostat) (Folder 5.32)
    - Hendrick Spring, undated; (1 item) (Folder 5.33)
    - Kaaterskill Falls; Junction of Kaaterskill and Spruce Creek, undated; (2 items) (Folder 5.34)
    - Morning and "Evening,", undated; (2 items) (Folder 5.35)
    - White Sulfur Spring, east side of Saratoga Lake, undated; (1 item) (Folder 5.36)
  - Miscellaneous Sketches
    - Sketch of two women [rejected for Vassar College and Its Founder; incl. letter to Lossing from Hannah Lyman, Lady Principal], circa 1867; (2 items) (Folder 5.37)
    - Vassar [pen and ink drawing of a man surrounded by women], 1886; (1 item) (Folder 5.38)
    - Sketch of various unidentified people, undated; (1 item, photostat) (Folder 5.39)
    - Sketch of Indian Pond on one side; sketches of various headstones on reverse side, undated; (1 item) (Folder 5.40)
    - Regimental flag of Dutchess County, NY, undated; (1 item) (Folder 5.41)
    - "Old Jamestown, from the river,", undated; (3 x 6 inches, graphite) (Folder 7.11)
    - "Wolfe-Montcalm Monument (Quebec),", undated; (7.5 x 6 inches, graphite and watercolor) (Folder 7.11)
- SERIES VII. PHOTOGRAPHS, circa 1860s - 1979
  - Photographs of Buildings
    - Lithograph of Vassar College, circa 1860s; (1 item) (Folder 6.1)
    - Lossing's home, Chestnut Ridge, Dover Plains, NY, circa 1880s; (1 item, oversized) (Folder 8.4)
    - Lossing's home, Dover Plains, NY, 1979; (5 items, color snapshots) (Folder 6.2)
  - Photographs of People
    - V.C. Faculty and Trustees: Dwight, William B. Hinkel, Charles Hinkel, Minna Leach, Abby Morse, Samuel F.B. Salmon, Lucy M. Whitney, Mary W., circa 1890; (7 items) (Folder 6.3)
    - VC Faculty and Trustees: Vassar, John Guy Vassar, Matthew, undated; (4 items) (Folder 6.4)
    - Colonel Larburshe, undated; (1 item) (Folder 6.5)
    - Smith, Colonel Morgan L., undated; (1 item, oversized) (Folder 8.5)
    - Photographs appearing in Vassar College and Its Founder; Anne Vassar; bust of Matthew Vassar; "Battle of Amazons,", undated; (3 items) (Folder 6.6)
- SERIES VIII. MEMORABILIA, 1723-1979
  - Biographical Material
    - Biographical notes by Mrs. Lossing to Mrs. Baxter, circa 1891; (MS, 9 p.) (Folder 6.7)
  - Acknowledgements
    - Gift Acknowledgement to Lossing from Harvard College, 1872; (1 item) (Folder 6.8)
  - Historical Society Memberships
    - Albany Institute American Antiquarian Society American Ethnological Society American Historical Association, 1856-1884; (6 items) (Folder 6.9)
    - American Institute of Civics, 1887; (1 item, oversized) (Folder 8.6)
    - Historical and Forestry Society of Rockland County [NY]; includes 2 letters to Lossing from Henry Whittemore, recording secretary, 1879; (3 items) (Folder 6.10)
    - Historical Society of Pennsylvania, 1851-1869; (2 items) (Folder 6.11)
    - Massachusetts Historical Society Minnesota Historical Society, 1861-1869; (3 items) (Folder 6.12)
    - New England Historical-Genealogical Society (see also Folder 8.6) New Jersey Historical Society New York Historical Society Newport [RI] Natural Historical Society, 1848-1890; (6 items) (Folder 6.13)
    - Northwestern Literary and Historical Society The Parthenian Society of the Baltimore Female College (see also Folder 8.6) Rhode Island Historical Society State Historical Society of Iowa State Historical Society of Wisconsin, 1856-1886; (7 items) (Folder 6.14)
    - Ulster [NY] Historical Society Virginia Historical Society Western Reserve [OH] Historical Society Worcester [MA] Society of Antiquity, 1860-1882; (5 items) (Folder 6.15)
  - Degrees
    - American Institute (see Folder 8.6) Hamilton College (honorary) University of Michigan (honorary), 1840-1872; (5 items) (Folder 6.16)
  - Invitations and Programs
    - 150th Regiment, 25th anniversary Lyndon-Hall School Commencement Programs, 1887-1890; (2 items) (Folder 6.17)
    - Vassar Female College Circular, circa 1865; (8 p., 2 copies) (Folder 6.18)
    - VC Anniversaries: programs; 25th anniversary Philaletheis 17th anniversary, 1882-1890; (3 items) (Folder 6.19)
    - VC Class Dar invitations, 1874-1885; ( 6 items) (Folder 6.20)
    - VC Commencement invitations, 1874-1885; (5 items) (Folder 6.21)
    - VC Commencement programs, 1875-1890; (4 items) (Folder 6.22)
    - VC Founder's Day invitation and program, 1866-1867; (2 items) (Folder 6.23)
    - VC Music Department invitations, 1866-1868; (3 items) (Folder 6.24)
    - VC Music Department programs, 1868-1890; (10 items) (Folder 6.25)
    - VC Trustees' Dinner program (annotated by Lossing), 1861; (1 item) (Folder 6.26)
    - Young Ladies' Academy, Ursuline Convent, Quebec prospectus, undated; (1 item) (Folder 6.27)
  - Newspaper Articles
    - Early History of Dutchess County; source: unknown [written by Lossing?], 1854; (1 item) (Folder 6.28)
    - Death of Professor Orton [in Dutchess Forum], 1877; (1 item) (Folder 6.29)
    - Matthew Vassar's Will and "The Charities of Matthew Vassar" [sources unknown], circa 1881; (2 items) (Folder 6.30)
    - Articles re: Vassar College Presidency, circa 1885; (3 items) (Folder 6.31)
    - A Presentation to Vassar College; [in Daily Eagle ], 1888; (1 item) (Folder 6.32)
    - The Gossip Tells Some Unpublished Authentic Anecdotes of Abraham Lincoln [interview with Lossing in Philadelphia Daily News ], 1890; (4 items) (Folder 6.33)
    - Lossing, Benson John [in Guide to American Historical Manuscripts in the Huntington Library ], 1979; (1 item) (Folder 6.34)
    - John Guy Vassar's Estate [source unknown], undated; (1 item) (Folder 6.35)
    - Vassar's Start [in Brooklyn Eagle], undated; (1 item) (Folder 6.36)
    - Women to Teach Women [annotated by Lossing, source unknown], undated; (1 item, oversized) (Folder 8.7)
  - Pamphlets